Guide to the James Buchanan Duke Papers, 1777-1999 and undated RL.00001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Pictures, 1870s-1960s and undated (bulk 1910s); 7
  - Duke, James B., funeral, 1925; 2 folders (Box 68)
    Photographs of funeral procession and crowds along Main St. and other parts of Durham, NC; mourners and wreaths at Duke Mausoleum in Maplewood Cemetery, Durham (where J.B. Duke was originally interred); family, mourners and hearse outside Duke Memorial Methodist Church, Durham; students, faculty and memorial wreaths at Duke University (East Campus)
  - Duke, Nanaline H., 1915 (Box 68)
  - Duke, Sarah P. and Jerry Markham (gate watchman, Southern R.R.), circa 1910s-1920s (Box 68)
    Identification of Markham based on caption of identical image in the Mildred Karnes Baldwin album
  - Duke, Washington: Underwood and Underwood studio portraits (armchair) (oversize), circa 1890s-1905 (Box 73)
  - Duke, Washington, circa 1890s-1905; undated; 5 photographs (Box 68)
    Includes prints of Underwood and Underwood armchair portrait (2 images), Washington Duke with bicycle (2 images), and the Washington Duke memorial statue on the Woman's College Campus [East Campus], Duke University
  - Few, Benjamin F.; Few, Mary R.with Frank Rounds, 1960s (Box 68)
  - Inman, Walker P., undated; 1 photograph and 1 negative (Box 68)
  - Perkins, William R., 1933 (Box 68)
  - Pickens, Marshall I., undated (Box 68)
  - Roney, Amos Kendall, Artelia Roney Duke Memorial Science Building, Elon College, North Carolina, undated (Box 69)
  - Sands, Alexander H., undated (Box 69)
  - Spence, Hersey Everett and Bessie Whitted Spence (Duke University) with Frank Rounds, circa 1960s (Box 69)
  - Staff and owners of British-American Tobacco Co. on the SS James B. Duke (oversize), undated (Oversize-folder 5)
  - Buildings and property: Duke Chapel Methodist Episcopal Church, South [Duke's Chapel United Methodist Church], Braggtown, Durham, NC (Horace Trumbauer drawings) (oversize), undated (Box 73)
  - Buildings and property: Duke Homestead; "Duke's First Factory" [barn], "Duke's mixture factory" (oversize), undated; 2 folders (Box 73)
  - Buildings and property: Duke Homestead (Washington Duke) and buildings, undated, 5 photographs (Box 69)
    Prints of Washington Duke on the porch of the the Duke Homestead dwelling; images of tobacco barns, one with Washington Duke standing beside it.
  - Buildings and property: Somerville, NJ, Estate: Postcards, circa 1907-1910; undated; 3 postcards, 2 photographs (Box 69)
    Includes black and white enlargements of two postcards
  - Buildings and property: Somerville, NJ, Estate: Hand-colored photographs: identified areas, undated; 2 folders; 20 photographs (Box 69)
  - Buildings and property: Somerville, NJ, Estate: Hand-colored photographs: unidentified areas, undated (Box 69)
  - Buildings and property: Somerville, NJ, Estate: Photograph of Horace Trumbauer's sketch of proposed mansion [never completed], circa 1911; 1975 (Box 69)
    Includes 1975 letter describing the background of the planning of the building.
  - Southern Power Co., Laying cornerstone of Great Falls Station on Catawba River, SC, 1905; 1 photographs (Box 69)
    Individuals pictured include W. S. Lee, Benjamin N. Duke, Dr. W. Gill Wylie, James B. Duke, and Mary Duke Biddle
  - Quebec Development Company, Saguenay River, Quebec, Canada: Photographic postcards, 1924; undated; 5 photographs (Box 69)
    Scenes of La Grande Decharge (Alma, Quebec), Isle Maligne Station cofferdam, and mixer house fire
  - Quebec Development Company, Saguenay River, Quebec, Canada: Photographic postcards of scenes from the construction of Isle Malign Station, undated, 23 photographs (Box 69)
  - Quebec Development Company, Saguenay River, Quebec, Canada: Photos of Isle Malign on Saguenay River, undated, 3 photographs (Box 69)
  - Quebec Development Company, Saguenay River, Quebec, Canada: Photos of staff of Quebec Development Company - identified individuals: D.F. Noyes, S.W. Myatt, Frank Harrison, undated, 2 photographs (Box 69)
  - Quebec Development Company, Saguenay River, Quebec, Canada: Souvenir photograph booklets, 1924; 2 booklets (Box 69)
    Photographs of construction of Isle Malign Station in Paper Manufacturers' Souvenir, 1924; Photographic map of Saguenay River in Programme of Summer Meeting for Saguenay Branch of the Engineering Institute of Canada, 1924, June 6.
  - Mildred Karnes Baldwin Album: List of album photographs; "Fairview" (home of Washington Duke) and extended Duke family, 1910-1912; 1950; undated; 10 photographs (Box 70)
  - Mildred Karnes Baldwin Album: Benjamin N. Duke and Sarah P. Duke, St. Petersburg, Florida, 1914; 2 photographs (Box 70)
    Pictures of the exterior of "Fairview," Washington Duke's house in Durham, and various extended family members and friends. Individuals pictured include Lida Duke Angier [Mrs. John C. Angier] Lillie Duke, John C. Angier, Mildred Karnes [Baldwin], J.D. Karnes, J. W. Karnes, W. C. Bradsher, Mrs. Bradsher, Mr. Dibbrel, S.W. Sparger, Dr. Pierce, Frances Green, Nancy Green Jones, and Nancy Karnes Bryant.
  - Mildred Karnes Baldwin Album: Duke Farms, Somerville, NJ and Myers Park, Charlotte, NC, 1925; undated; 7 photographs (Box 70)
  - Mildred Karnes Baldwin Album: James B. Duke, Benjamin N. Duke and W. W. Flowers, Atlantic City, NJ; James B. Duke and Benjamin N. Duke, Charlotte, NC, 1920; 1924; 3 photographs (Box 70)
    Photographs of J.B. Duke's car; the fountain, greenhouse, and offices at Duke Farms; J.B. Duke and Lucille Shane in New Jersey, and a social gathering at J.B. Duke's mansion in Myers Park, Charlotte, NC.
  - Mildred Karnes Baldwin Album: Benjamin N. Duke, circa 1910s-1920s; Sarah P. Duke and Jerry Markham (gate watchman, Southern R.R.), 1916; undated; 2 photographs (Box 70)
  - Mildred Karnes Baldwin Album: James B. Duke, Lucille Shane, and Eustice Crocker (chauffeur), New Jersey, 1925; 1 photographs (Box 70)
  - Negatives: Mildred Karnes Baldwin album, 1910-1925; undated; 1 of 6 (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Negatives: Mildred Karnes Baldwin album, 1910-1925; undated; 2 of 6 (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Negatives: Mildred Karnes Baldwin album, 1910-1925; undated; 3 of 6 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Negatives: Mildred Karnes Baldwin album, 1910-1925; undated; 4 of 6 (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Negatives: Mildred Karnes Baldwin album, 1910-1925; undated; 5 of 6 (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Negatives: Mildred Karnes Baldwin album, 1910-1925; undated; 6 of 6 (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Negatives: Duke, James B.: Painting by John DaCosta, 2 color negatives (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - Negatives: Duke, James B. and Benjamin N., Atlantic City, New Jersey, circa 1920s; 1 of 2 (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - Negatives: Duke, James B. and Benjamin N., Atlantic City, New Jersey, circa 1920s; 2 of 2 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    Original pellicle removed from deteriorated acetate base by Chicago Albumen Works, December 2014.
    Conditions Governing Access
    Access to the fragile pellicle is restricted. Please consult digital use copy.
  - Negatives: Duke, James B. and unidentified man: mill visit, circa 1900s-1910s (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Negatives: Duke, James B. and Caleb C. Dula (Box 71, Folder 9)
  - Negatives: Duke, James B., Benjamin N., and others, circa 1920s; 1 of 2 (Box 71, Folder 10)
  - Negatives: Duke, James B., Benjamin N., and others, circa 1920s; 2 of 2 (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - Negatives: Duke, Benjamin N. (Box 71, Folder 12)
  - Negatives: Duke, James B., Benjamin N., Washington, and others near Erwin, NC, circa 1902-1904 (Box 71, Folder 11)
  - Negatives: Duke, Benjamin N. and Sarah P., Atlantic City, New Jersey, circa 1924 (Box 71, Folder 13)
  - Motion picture: James B. Duke and Caleb C. Dula at Dula's residence, Yonkers, New York (16mm copy print and negative), undated; 2 Reels (Box 72)
    No audio
  - Motion picture: James B. Duke and Caleb C. Dula at Dula's residence, Yonkers, New York (VHS use copy), undated (Box 72)